<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lokadhatu Myriadis</title>
    <link>https://lokadhatu.com/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lokadhatu Myriadis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2015-2024 Lokadhatu Myriadis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://lokadhatu.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Keju in Anglo-American countries</title>
        <link>https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20151031_keju_in_anglo_american_countries/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 18:45:26 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20151031_keju_in_anglo_american_countries/</guid>
        <description>Lokadhatu Myriadis https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20151031_keju_in_anglo_american_countries/ -&lt;p&gt;In the 19th century, the British Empire was the global hegemon, playing a pivotal role in the dissemination of technologies and institutional frameworks. This era saw significant disparities in the timing of technological adoption and institutional reform across different regions. The Industrial Revolution, which originated in the United Kingdom in the mid-18th century, did not permeate the European continent or the Americas until the first half of the 19th century. A similar pattern was observed in the adoption of institutional reforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One notable example of institutional borrowing was the British Empire&amp;rsquo;s introduction of a civil examination system inspired by the Chinese Keju (科舉). Thomas Taylor Meadows, a British consul in Guangzhou following the First Opium War, observed in his 1847 work, &amp;lsquo;Desultory Notes on the Government and People of China,&amp;rsquo; that &amp;ldquo;the long duration of the Chinese empire is solely and altogether owing to the good government which consists in the advancement of men of talent and merit only.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by this meritocratic system, the British Empire eventually established Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Civil Service in 1853 and the Imperial Civil Service in British India in 1858, shortly after the Indian Rebellion of 1857. The United States followed suit, adopting the Pendleton Civil Service Reform Act in 1883, establishing a similar merit-based selection process for civil servants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adoption of civil examinations across these diverse contexts was driven by a shared objective: to enhance the stability and efficiency of their political systems by selecting civil servants based on merit rather than nepotism or patronage. This transition towards meritocracy reflects a significant shift in governance philosophies, influenced by cross-cultural exchanges and the recognition of the long-term benefits of institutional reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meadows, T. T. (1847). Desultory Notes on the Government and People of China, and on the Chines Language;: Illustrated with a Sketch of the Province of Kwang-Tûng, Shewing Its Division Into Departments and Districts. Wm. H. Allen and Company, 7, Leadenhall Street.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20151031_keju_in_anglo_american_countries/ - 2015-2024 Lokadhatu Myriadis</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Misinterpretation</title>
        <link>https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20150712_misinterpretation_of_frankflin/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 16:01:30 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20150712_misinterpretation_of_frankflin/</guid>
        <description>Lokadhatu Myriadis https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20150712_misinterpretation_of_frankflin/ -&lt;p&gt;People often quote the famous remark of Ben Franklin, &amp;ldquo;[t]hey who can give up essential liberty to obtain a little temporary safety, deserve neither liberty nor safety&amp;rdquo;, to criticize governments&amp;rsquo; attempts of storing digital data generated by netizens, especially for those people living in West Europa, where privacy is regarded as one of the most important human rights. However, not to mention the justice of such measures taken by governements, there is perhaps a misinterpretation of the remark of Franklin made by people who quoted it. In order to understand the remark it would be better to go back to the context in which Franklin expressed it. In his article &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lawfareblog.com/what-ben-franklin-really-said&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What Ben Frankflin Really Said&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, Benjamin Wittes well elucidated the real meaning of liberty and safety in Franklin&amp;rsquo;s context. In short, what Franklin meant under the word &amp;ldquo;liberty&amp;rdquo; was the liberty of Pennsylvania Assembly to levy a tax on the Penn Family&amp;rsquo;s lands for financing the French and Indian Wars, while &amp;ldquo;purchase a temporary safety&amp;rdquo; refers to Penn Family&amp;rsquo;s attempt to avoidance of being taxed by offering some financial support for the wars.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://lokadhatu.com/en/posts/essay_20150712_misinterpretation_of_frankflin/ - 2015-2024 Lokadhatu Myriadis</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 